IAN LOVEALL: Hi.
Now here's another example of lighting.
Lighting is what is going to create the illusion that you're looking at something that isn't actually there.
For example, this alcove, we see the key elements of light and shadow.
You have your high light, your low light, your core shadow, your cast shadow and your reflected light.
So, what we're looking at here is a basic setup of the basic elements of light and shadow as we have our high light, our low light, core shadow, cast shadow and reflected light.
Now the high light is an area on an object that's receiving a direct blow from the light source which is behind me here, the window, and that would be this edge of the urn right here.
The low light is an area of the object that's not quite in direct light but it's still receiving some light and that would be this middle section here.
And then as this urn curves away from the light source, we're going to get our core shadow which is the darkest point on the object that's receiving the least amount of light.
And then, of course, the blockage created by the object will create a cast shadow against the wall which we see here.
Some of that light, however, will bounce back from this wall onto the object and that creates our reflected light.
If you see here along the edge, there's just a little bit of light from this wall that's being bounced back at the urn.